darden.com 2017-10-05

# Online Privacy Notice - Your Privacy Rights | Darden Restaurants

We at Darden Corporation, along with our affiliates (collectively, “Darden,” “we,” “our,” “us”), respect your concerns about privacy. This Privacy Notice applies to our use of personal information that we may collect at Darden locations in the United States and via online and mobile services that link to this Privacy Notice (collectively, the “Services”).

This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on the Sites, how we may use the information, with whom we may share it and the choices available to you regarding our use of the information. We also describe the measures we take to safeguard the information and tell you how to contact us about our privacy practices.

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:
    Information We Collect  
How We Use The Information We Collect  
Interest-Based Advertising  
Information We Share  
Your Options  
Notice to Canadian Residents  
Cross-Border Transfer  
Notice to California Residents  
Do Not Track Policy  
Links To Other Websites  
How We Protect Personal Information  
Children's Privacy  
Updates To Our Privacy Notice  
How To Contact Us
     
Information We Collect

We may obtain certain personal information (such as name and other contact details) through our Sites. The types of personal information we may collect include:

  * Contact information, such as your name, postal address, e-mail address, and telephone number;
  * Names, postal addresses, e-mail addresses and telephone numbers of others to whom you ask us to send information;
  * Username and password to access Darden products and services online;
  * Payment information (such as payment card details, financial account information and billing address);
  * Birth date;
  * Online order history;
  * Information about your education, work and military history, legal work eligibility status, and other information relevant to specific jobs for which you may apply; and
  * Other personal information you may provide to us.

In addition, when you visit our Sites, we may collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons. The information we collect in this manner includes IP address, browser characteristics, device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, information on actions taken on our site, and dates and times of website visits. A "cookie" is a text file that websites send to a visitor's computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A "web beacon", also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server. Through these automated collection methods, we obtain "clickstream data", which is a log of content on which a visitor clicks while browsing a website. As the visitor clicks through the website, a record of the action may be collected and stored. We may link certain data elements we have collected through automated means, such as your browser information, with other information we have obtained about you to let us know, for example, whether you have opened an e-mail we sent to you. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies or how to restrict or disable certain types of cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our Sites. See also our "Do Not Track Policy" below.

If you use Site features operated by third-party social networking services (such as Facebook), we may receive information you have made available to those services, including the geographic location of your mobile device and other information about you (such as name, email address, gender, locale, time zone, languages, social media profile URL, personal website URL, biographical information, birthday, photo, list of devices, education history, work history, hometown, interests, current city, political views, favorite athlete and teams, relationship status and information, religion, name of significant other, and certain security settings information) and your contacts on those services. Some of these social networking services allow you to push content from our Sites to your contacts or to pull information about your contacts so you can connect with them on our Sites. Some of these services also will facilitate your registration for our Sites or enhance or personalize your experience on our Sites. You should make sure you understand the information your third-party social networking services may make available to our Sites. We may use and disclose the personal information we receive on our Sites through third-party social networking services as described in this Privacy Notice.

Top of Page

How We Use The Information We Collect

We may use the information we obtain through the Sites to:

  * Create and manage your account;
  * Offer and provide products and services to you;
  * Process and collect payments for gift cards;
  * Communicate about, and administer your participation in, special events, programs, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, and other offers or promotions;
  * Combine it with information we receive offline to send you offers or promotions;
  * Send information to others if you ask us to do so;
  * Respond to and communicate with you about your requests, questions and comments;
  * Manage your application for employment with Darden and contact you in connection with potential employment opportunities;
  * Process claims we receive in connection with our products and services;
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our sales, marketing and advertising; analyzing and enhancing our products, services and Sites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * Perform data analyses and other processing (including market and consumer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, anonymization, encryption and tokenization of personal information);
  * Protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities; and
  * Comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards and our policies.

In addition, we use information collected online through cookies, local shared objects (also known as "Flash cookies"), web beacons and other automated means for purposes such as: (i) customizing our users' visits to our Sites, (ii) delivering content (including advertising) tailored to our users' interests; and the manner in which our users browse our Sites, and (iii) managing our business. We may supplement data we collect through automated means with information about your location (such as your zip code) to provide you with content that may be of interest to you. We also use this information to help diagnose technical and service problems, administer our Sites, identify users of our Sites, and gather demographic information about our users. We use clickstream data to determine how much time users spend on web pages of our Sites, how users navigate through our Sites, and how we may tailor our Sites to better meet the needs of our users. To identify local shared objects on your computer and adjust your settings, please visit: [www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html)

We may use third-party web analytics services on our Sites, such as those of Google Analytics. The analytics providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyze how visitors use the Sites. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to these analytics providers, who use the information to evaluate use of the Sites. To learn more about Google Analytics and how to opt out, please visit: [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). We may combine information we collect from you with information we receive from third parties and use it for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice. We also may use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

Top of Page

Interest-Based Advertising

On the Sites, we may collect information about your online activities for use in providing you with advertising about products and services tailored to your individual interests. This section of our Privacy Notice provides details and explains how to exercise your choices.

You may see certain ads on other websites based on your visits to our Sites because we participate in advertising networks administered by third-party vendors. Ad networks allow us to target our messaging to users through demographic, interest-based and contextual means. These networks track your online activities over time by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of cookies, web server logs and web beacons. The networks use this information to show you advertisements that are tailored to your individual interests. The information our ad network vendors collect includes information about your visits to websites that participate in the vendors' advertising networks, such as the pages or advertisements you view and the actions you take on the websites. This data collection takes place both on these Sites and on third-party websites that participate in the ad networks. This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. To learn more about how to opt out of ad network interest-based advertising, please visit: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

Top of Page

Information We Share

We do not sell or otherwise share personal information about you, except as described in this Privacy Notice. When you post a comment on our blogs, we may publish your name and user ID on the blog with your comment. We share personal information with third parties who perform services on our behalf based on our instructions. These third parties are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. We also may share the personal information we obtain with our affiliates, franchisees and joint marketing partners.

We also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena), (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation).

Top of Page

Your Options

We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you. To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our newsletter e-mail lists or submit a request, please contact us as specified in the "How To Contact Us" section of this Privacy Notice.

Top of Page

Notice to Canadian Residents

We collect, use and disclose your personal information with your consent, which may be express or implied. You may withdraw your consent to the use and disclosure of your personal information by us or by third parties for marketing purposes at any time by contacting us as specified below under "How to Contact Us." If you would like to access, update or ask us to delete your preferences or the personal information that we have collected about you, please contact us, and we will respond to your request within 30 days.

Top of Page

Cross-Border Transfer

Your personal information may be processed, used, stored, or accessed in the United States or other countries where we have operations, and may be subject to the laws of those countries including requirements to disclose information to government authorities, courts or law enforcement agencies.

Top of Page

Notice to California Residents

Subject to certain limits under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us as specified in the "How to Contact Us" section below.

Top of Page

Do Not Track Policy

Our website is not designed to respond to "do not track" signals received from browsers.

Top of Page

Links To Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may be operated by companies not affiliated with Darden. Linked websites may have their own privacy policies or notices, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with Darden, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

Top of Page

How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

Top of Page

Children's Privacy

Our Sites are not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on our Sites. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on our Sites, we will delete the information from our records.

Top of Page

Updates To Our Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Notice and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.

Top of Page

How To Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by e-mail at [privacy@darden.com](mailto:privacy@darden.com) or by phone at 407-245-5397, ext. 7. You also may write to us at:

Ethics & Compliance Office  
Darden Restaurants, Inc.  
1000 Darden Center Drive  
Orlando, FL 32837

Please note that on occasion, third parties unaffiliated with us may conduct marketing campaigns where they offer gift cards to our restaurants, which they have purchased separately, as inducements to enroll in their programs, complete surveys or take other actions. In such cases, requests directed to us to opt out of further communications will not be effective, as we have no control over the activities of such third parties.

Top of Page
